Back for War.
The Expendables 2 is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Simon West.
Church reunites the Expendables for what should be an easy paycheck, but when one of their men is murdered on the
job, their quest for revenge puts them deep in enemy territory and up against an unexpected threat.
Barney Ross, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Lee Christmas, played by Jason Statham.
Yin Yang, played by Jet Li.
Gunner Jensen, played by Dolph Lundgren.
Booker, played by Chuck Norris.
Jean Vilain, played by Jean-Claude Van Damme.
The Expendables 2 is a 2012 American action film directed by Simon West, written by Richard Wenk
and Sylvester Stallone and based on a story by Ken Kaufman, David Agosto and Wenk.
Brian Tyler returned to score the film.
It is the sequel to The Expendables (2010), and is the
second installment in The Expendables franchise.
The film stars an ensemble cast of largely action film actors consisting of Sylvester Stallone, Jason Statham, Jet Li, Dolph Lundgren,
Chuck Norris, Randy Couture, Terry Crews, Liam Hemsworth, Jean-Claude Van Damme, Bruce Willis, and Arnold Schwarzenegger.
In the film, The Expendables undertake a mission which evolves into a quest for revenge against rival
mercenary Jean Vilain, who murders one of their own men and threatens the world with a deadly weapon.
Principal photography took place over 14 weeks (beginning in
September 2011) on an estimated $100 million budget.
Film locations included Bulgaria, Hong Kong and New Orleans.
Controversy arose over the accidental death of a stuntman and
environmental damage caused during filming in Bulgaria.
The film was released in Europe on August 16, 2012,
and in North America the following day.
The Expendables 2 grossed  $315 million worldwide, with
its greatest success outside North America.
Critics generally considered the film an improvement over its predecessor due to its increased
use of humor and action sequences, but its plot and dialogues received criticism.
A tie-in downloadable video game was released on July 31,
2012 as a prequel to the events of the film.
A sequel titled The Expendables 3 was released on August 15, 2014.
The film explores themes of airplane, loss of loved
one, mercenary, airplane crash, beard.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.